### **STEPHEN ORYEMA**

Kampala, Uganda

+256771634966/+256750098228 || oryemasteve9@gmail.com || LinkedIn || GitHub || Portfolio

#### PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a passionate Fullstack developer with 1 year of experience in developing and implementing innovative software solutions. I am dedicated to delivering software solutions that drive business success. I am eager to learn and contribute my expertise to a forward-thinking organization that values innovation, teamwork, and continuous learning.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Fullstack Web developer trainee

Remote

Tunga Tech Impact Academy

Aug, 2023 to Present

- Collaborated with a team to develop human resource management system that help companies manage their employees' onboarding, attendance and leave.
- Developed a personal movie database web application to store and track my favorite movies and series.
- Designed and developed a web application for managing user's shopping list.
- Addressed and fixed complex bugs.

#### Hydrogeologist

Drilling Spares and Services Limited Kampala, Uganda

April, 2022 to present

- Supervise groundwater drilling, well design, casing installation and prepare geologic logs of production wells and monitoring wells achieving 90% success rate,
- Collect and analyze aquifer test data including water level measurement, hydraulic conductivity tests and water quality testing and contaminants in the water,
- Prepare technical reports and presentations to communicate findings and recommendations to the clients and stakeholders,
- work while adhering to health and safety protocols ranging from corporate policies to client specific programs.

## Web developer/Data analyst

Freelance, Remote May, 2020- Feb, 2022

- Developed websites and mobile applications,
- Carried out data collection, cleaning, visualization, analysis and presentation of insights.
- Worked on personal projects such as Rental app UI, BMI Calculator app, Calculator app, To do app etc.
- Conducted data cleaning, visualization and presentation using Python, Power BI, Advanced MS Excel and SQL.

### **PROJECTS**

**StephDB** [HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Nodejs, Expressjs, MySQL]

link GitHub

- This is a personal movie database that helps users store their favorite movies and series for future reference. It allows users to search for the movie or series from an online API and add the specific movie to their personal database.
- Built the frontend using HTML, CSS and JavaScript, and backend using Nodejs, Expressis and MySQL database.

### PlutoHR (Employee Management system) [CSS, Reactjs, Django and SQLite]

<u>link</u> <u>GitHub</u>

- This was a collaboration project.
- The project is an online web application that allows employers to onboard employees, track employee attendance and leave records. Employers approves or rejects leave requests from employees.
- Built the UI using Reactis and CSS for styling, Diango for backend and SQLite database.

### My Shopping List app [HTML, CSS, JavaScript, NodeJS, Expressjs and MySQL]

<u>link</u> <u>GitHub</u>

- The project is an online shopping list tracking app.
- Built the UI using HTML and CSS and made functionalities using JavaScript.

## MyShop (Ecommerce website) [HTML, CSS, JavaScript]

<u>link</u> <u>GitHub</u>

- The project is an online ecommerce website where customers can go through products and add to cart. It allows you to update cart.
- Built the UI using HTML and CSS and made functionalities using JavaScript.

- This is a web application to allow EatUp restaurant customers to see the menu and order food.
- The project has a landing page for the restaurant, menu page where users look through available meals and their prices, users can order for food online,
- Built the UI using HTML and CSS and made functionalities using JavaScript. It is still in progress.

### Personal Portfolio [HTML, CSS, JavaScript]

<u>link</u> <u>GitHub</u>

- This is my personal portfolio project to showcase my skills.
- My experience, projects and contacts are listed here.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Makerere University**

Bachelor of Science in Petroleum Geoscience and Production

Aug, 2016 - May 2021

King's College Budo Feb, 2014 - Dec, 2015

Uganda Advanced Certificate of Education (UACE)

#### **SKILLS**

**Technical Skills:** HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ReactJS, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Git, Python (Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn), MySQL, PostgreSQL, Systems Logic, Software Troubleshooting.

**Soft Skills:** Problem solving, Clear communication skills, strong leadership skills, advanced analytical skills, good pressure management, team player.

Fun Activities: Reading, Lover of Fiction movies, Nature walking, Indoor exercises.

#### **CERTFICATIONS**

•	Fullstack developer trainee at Tunga Tech Impact Academy	Jan,2024 - June, 2024.
•	Legacy JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures, FreeCodeCamp	2024
•	Datacamp Certified: Data Analyst Associate, DataCamp	2023
•	Applied Data Science, WorldQuant University	2023
•	Responsive Web Design certificate, FreeCodeCamp	2021

## **LANGUAGE**

- English -Fluent in spoken and written
- Luo (Alur) Native language
- Luganda, Beginner

# **REFEREES**

### 1. Mr. SUNDAY DEOGRATIAS

Software Engineer, Yoya Consultancy Uganda Limited +256786684227/+256700659758 sundaydeogratias8@gmail.com

## 2. Mr. TAIYE SULEIMAN

Lead Software Engineering facilitator
Tunga

taiyesuleiman09@gmail.com